

## Bongekile Adonica Gasa

Contact Number: 079 972 2120 Email: adonicabgasa1995@gmail.com

## **Objective Statement**

I am an associate designate, awaiting admission.

I worked in the Intellectual Property department at Norton Rose Fulbright South Africa Inc, based in the Durban office.

I completed my articles of clerkship at Norton Rose Fulbright South Africa Inc, Sandton, Johannesburg between 2021 – 2022. Having completed three core rotations, I have experience and exposure in Intellectual Property, Insurance, Medical Negligence and Commercial Litigation. I was subsequently retained in the Intellectual Property department, where I previously served a 12-month rotation in 2022.

I gained exposure and experience in both trademark prosecution and intellectual property disputes. I assisted with IP disputes, copyright infringements, takedowns, notices, letters of demand, licensing and assignment agreements, advisory on the protection of intellectual property, assistance with infringements thereof and due diligences. I also assisted with trademark portfolio management.

I have worked with various clients such as SABC, Honor, Afrisam and Continental Food Brands to mention a few.

I am a young, talented and hardworking attorney awaiting admission, who is driven to deliver results. I am innovative, solution resolutive and I think out of the box, which allows me to offer a transformative touch to the legal profession. I am able to work independently and require minimum supervision. I am efficient and work well under pressure.

I hold a BA and LLB from the University of the Witwatersrand. I have completed and passed the Trade mark examination with South African Institute of Intellectual Property Law (SAIIPL) in September 2023. I intend taking the copyright exam and completing the Group One examinations.

### **Notable Skills**

- Presentation skills
- ➤ Well –spoken
- Solution driven
- Communication skills
- > Relation building
- Meticulous / attention to detail

Efficient and independent

- Team player

- Drafting
- > Research
- Multi-tasking
- ➤ Use of Word
- > Typing

## Education

- > 2013 Matric Greenside High School
- > 2014 2020 The University of the Witwatersrand
- > 2021 2022 Law Society of South Africa LEAD legal course completion
- 2023 Completed Legal Practice Council requirements for admission as practicing Attorney – awaiting admission

## **Employment History**

**Title** – Offshore Administrator (**2015- 2017**) **Bizinsure**, **San Francisco** 

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Assisted with marketing and selling business insurance products to potential clients
- Assisted with general administrative management and tasks
- General functionality of business and its respective model

Title - Tutor (2017-2019) Gutsy tutoring, Cape Town, South Africa

**Duties and Responsibilities:** 

Assisted with extra classes

- Provided English and History classes, at foundation and high school phase
- > Provided Bachelor of Arts subject assistance

# Title – Candidate Attorney (2021 -2022) Norton Rose Fulbright South Africa, Johannesburg

#### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

\*rotations – Litigation Insurance, Commercial Litigation, Intellectual Property

- > Serving relevant documentation on opposition parties
- Research
- First drafts of notices, opinions, various legal documents, letters of demand
- Pagination and court file compilation
- > Appearance in the Magistrate's Courts
- Attending to set downs and various court processes
- Assistance at Magistrate Courts social desk services for gender-based violence
- Assistance with maintenance and divorce matters
- > Probono, virtual clinic and consultations,

## Title – Associate Designate (2023 – present) Norton Rose Fulbright South Africa, Durban

#### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

- Commercial litigation work
- > Business law related claims, queries and relevant drafts
- > Drafting various legal documents
- > Research
- Compiling opinions and advisory notes
- > Social impact work and virtual clinical consultations
- > Court set downs and appearances
- > Instituting and defending claims and infringements

## Languages

- ➤ English Excellent
- > Afrikaans Moderate
- ➤ IsiZulu Excellent
- ➤ IsiNdebele Excellent
- ➤ Tswana Excellent

### **Publications**

- 1. "Distinguishing trademark and patent protection and the Nespresso coffee capsules court battle" https://www.financialinstitutionslegalsnapshot.com/2022/03/distinguishing-trademark-and-patent-protection-and-the-nespresso-coffee-capsules-court-battle/
- 2. Intellectual property enforcement: "Another arrow in our quiver" https://www.financialinstitutionslegalsnapshot.com/2022/10/intellectual-property-enforcement-another-arrow-in-our-quiver/

## References

#### 1. Daniel Scott

CEO and President of BizinsureContact Number: 012 327 9400

> Cell: 0016508043368

> Email: scott.daniel.p@gmail.com

#### 2. Zulma Bastedo

> Head of Sales

> Email: zulma@bizinsure.com

#### 3. Carla Gusty

Founder of Gusty Tutoring and Recruit

Contact Number: 081 396 7039Email: <a href="mailto:carla@gustytutoring.co.za">carla@gustytutoring.co.za</a>

#### 4. Ketlotse Sekoko

- > Human Resources Business Partner Norton Rose Fulbright South Africa Inc
- Contact Number: 061 437 7607 / 071 435 1096
- Email: <u>Ksekoko@gmail.com</u>

#### 5. Candice Pillay

- Director at Norton Rose South Africa Inc Social Impact
- Contact Number: 082 497 3060
- > Email: <u>Candice.Pillay@nortonrosefulbright.com</u>